samplesource.com 2016-10-18

# SampleSource.com - Free Samples - home, health, beauty, makeup, food, and more!

Effective date: January 1, 2014

This Privacy Notice has been prepared by SampleSource Incorporated for Canadian visitors and SampleSource USA Incorporated for US visitors (collectively, "SampleSource", "we", "us" or "our"), and it sets out the manner in which SampleSource collects, uses, discloses and otherwise manages personal information.  This Privacy Notice applies to the privacy practices on our websites located at [www.samplesource.com](http://www.samplesource.com/?site=us) and [www.samplesource.ca](http://www.samplesource.ca/) (the "Website").

##  Collection and Use Of Personal Information

The term “personal information” means information about an identifiable individual, including but not limited to full name, address, email address, and other information relating to an individual.

We may collect personal information when you: 

• Make a request on the Website to receive samples;  
• Participate in our contests, sweepstakes or promotions;  
• Check the status of your order;  
• Complete a survey available through our Website;  
• Sign up to receive promotional email and other communications;  
• Contact us with a comment, question or complaint.

**Request Samples:** When you register to request samples on our Website, we collect certain personal information such as your name, mailing address, username and a password. You may also opt to provide your cell phone number to receive text alerts when samples are available. When you register, you will have the opportunity to provide certain demographic information, such as your gender, marital and employment status, household income, number of children, whether you own pets, and shopping habits.  This additional demographic information is optional, however, please note that product manufacturers frequently limit sampling opportunities to individuals who fall within certain demographics.  As a result, if you decide not to provide additional optional demographic information, you may not be able to take advantage of all of our sampling offers.

**Contests, Sweepstakes and Promotions:** When you enter a contest, sweepstakes or participate in a promotion, we may collect your name, address, phone number, email address, and other information you provide.  We use this information to administer your participation in the contest, sweepstakes or promotion.  At the time you enter the contest, sweepstakes or promotion, we may obtain your consent to send you future promotional communications.  If a contest, sweepstakes or promotion is jointly sponsored by us and one or more sponsors, your personal information may be shared with such sponsors, as specified at the time of collection of your personal information.  We do not control the use, disclosure or security of your personal information by other sponsors, and recommend you review their respective privacy notices or statements.

The “TELL A FRIEND” and other similar features on our Website permit you to send email to others.  This feature requires you to submit your name and email address, as well as the name and email address of the recipient.  We do not use the names or email addresses submitted in these circumstances for any other purpose without the consent of you or the email recipient to do so. 

**Trusted Partners.** When you make a request to receive samples through our Website, you may choose to opt-in to receive additional offers from our trusted SampleSource partners.  These offers may be sent by direct mail and/or e-mail from our trusted partners or directly from us on behalf of our partners.  If you opt-in, we may share the personal information you provide to SampleSource (including your name, mailing address, and optional demographic information) with our partners. 

**Check the Status of Your Order:** We offer you the opportunity to provide your email address to check on the status of your order on our Website. We use this information to track your order.

**Email and Other Communications:** From time to time, we may obtain your consent to send you email and other communications about products, services, promotions or events relating to SampleSource that may be of interest to you. 

## Your choices: 

Our policy is to not disclose your personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes unless we first obtain your opt-in consent. 

You can opt-out of receiving promotional messages from us by doing one of the following:

• If you have received an email, you can follow the opt-out or "unsubscribe" instructions provided in your email.   
• If you have received a text message, you unsubscribe by replying with “STOP”.  
• You can always request to be unsubscribed by contacting us through the "Contact Us" page on our Website or using the contact information set out below.

**Contact Us:** When you contact us with a comment, question or complaint, you may be asked to provide personal information (such as your name, address, email address and a phone number) along with additional information we need to help us promptly answer your question or respond to your comment or complaint.  We may also retain this information to assist you in the future and to improve our customer service, product and service offerings, and events and promotions. 

## Disclosure of Personal Information  

Our policy is that we will not disclose, trade, rent, sell or otherwise transfer your personal information, without your consent, except as otherwise set out herein.  We may maintain or process your personal information in the US or other jurisdictions.

**Service Provider Arrangements:** We may transfer (or otherwise make available) your personal information to third parties who provide services on our behalf.  For example, we may use service providers to authorize and process sample orders, host our Website, operate certain of its features, serve advertisements on our Website, send email or other communications, or run our contests and promotions.

Your personal information may be maintained and processed by our service providers in the US or other jurisdictions.  Our service providers are given the information they need to perform their designated functions, and we do not authorize them to use or disclose personal information for their own marketing or other purposes. 

**Ratings/Reviews:** If you provide a product rating and/or review and choose to permit SampleSource and the brands whose products you try to use your feedback to help others make smart shopping decisions, SampleSource may use personal information you have provided such as your first name and last initial, city and province/state, gender, product rating or review, your public IP address at the time of submitting the Review, and other information you provide about your experience with the product (the “Review”) for the purposes of displaying the Review to the public. SampleSource may also provide this information to the brands whose products you have tried, and if applicable, their service provider. The public IP address is disclosed to the brand partner or their service provider for review fraud detection and mitigation purposes.

**Sale of Business:** We may transfer any information we have about you as an asset in connection with a merger or sale (including transfers made as part of insolvency or bankruptcy proceedings) involving all or part of SampleSource or as part of a corporate reorganization or stock sale or other change in corporate control.

**Legal:** SampleSource and our Canadian, US and other service providers may provide your personal information in response to a search warrant or other legally valid inquiry or order, or to an investigative body in the case of a breach of an agreement or contravention of law, or as otherwise required by applicable Canadian, US or other law.  We may also disclose personal information where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, or as otherwise permitted by law.

##  Additional Information about our Website

**Visiting our Website:** Visiting our Website: In general, you can visit our Website without telling us who you are or submitting any personal information. However, we collect the IP (Internet Protocol) addresses of visitors to our Website and other information about your visit, such as page requests, browser type, operating system and average time spent on our Website.  We use this information to help us understand our Website activity, and to monitor and improve our Website.

**Cookies:** Our Website uses a technology called "cookies".  A cookie is a tiny element of data that our Website can send to your browser, which is stored on your hard drive so we may later be able to recognize your computer or other device when you return.  If you have registered with our Website, cookies may provide us and our service providers with information that we will use to personalize our Website in accordance with your preferences.  Most Web browsers allow you to modify your settings to notify you when you receive a cookie or to reject cookies entirely.  However, if you decide not to accept cookies from our Website, you may not be able to take advantage of all of the features of our Website.

We may also use a third party to help us gather and analyze information about the areas that you visit on the Website to evaluate and improve the customer experience and the convenience of the Website, and to help us evaluate some of the specific information related to your Website visits. 

**Tracer Tags & Web Beacons: **Our Website may also use a technology called "tracer tags" or “Web Beacons”.  This technology allows us to understand which pages you visit on our Website. These tracer tags are used to help us optimize and tailor our Website for you and other future visitors to our Website.

We may also use third parties to serve our advertisements on other websites.  These companies may use tracer tags or web beacons to report certain information (but not your name, address, e-mail address or telephone number) about your visits to our Website and the websites which advertise and feature links to our Website, in order to measure the effectiveness of our advertisements. 

**Third party links:** Our Website may contain links to other sites that SampleSource does not own or operate.  Also, links to our Website may be featured on third party websites on which we advertise.  Except as provided herein, our policy is that we will not provide any of your personal information to these third parties without your consent.  We provide links to third party websites as a convenience to the user.  These links are not intended as an endorsement of or referral to the linked websites.  The linked websites have separate and independent privacy statements, notices and terms of use, which we recommend you read carefully.  We do not have any control over such websites, and therefore we have no responsibility or liability for the manner in which the organizations that operate such linked websites may collect, use or disclose, secure and otherwise treat your personal information.

**Children:** Our Website is not intended for children under 13 and therefore we do not intend to collect personal information from children under the age of 13.  If you are 13 or older, but under the age of majority in the jurisdiction in which you live, you must have your parent or legal guardian’s permission to use our Websites, register or participate in any promotional offers.

##  Security of Personal Information

We have implemented measures designed to help protect personal information in our custody and control.  We maintain reasonable administrative, technical and physical safeguards in an effort to protect against unauthorized access, use, modification and disclosure of personal information in our custody and control. Unfortunately, no collection or transmission of information over the Internet or other publicly accessible communications networks can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, and therefore, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any such information.

We have personal information retention processes designed to retain personal information of our customers for no longer than necessary for the purposes stated above or to otherwise meet legal requirements. 

##  Access to your Personal Information

You have the right to access, update, and correct inaccuracies in your personal information in our custody and control, subject to certain exceptions prescribed by law.  You may request access, updating and corrections of inaccuracies in personal information we have in our custody or control by emailing or writing to us at the contact information set out below.  We may request certain personal information for the purposes of verifying the identity of the individual seeking access to their personal information records.

##  Changes to the Privacy Notice

This Privacy Notice may be updated periodically to reflect changes to our personal information practices. The revised Privacy Notice will be posted on this Website. If we make material changes to this Privacy Notice, we will notify you by posting a notice on the front page of this Website. We strongly encourage you to please refer to this Privacy Notice often for the latest information about our personal information practices.  The Effective Date of this Privacy Notice is posted at the top of this page.

##  Contacting our Privacy Officer

Please contact us if:

• you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Notice,   
• you wish to opt-out of marketing emails, or access, update, and/or correct inaccuracies in your personal information, or   
• you otherwise have a question or complaint about the manner in which we treat your personal information. 

By email to [privacy.info@samplesource.com](mailto:privacy.info@samplesource.com) or

By mail to SampleSource, 34 Eglinton Avenue West, Unit 170, Toronto, Ontario, Canada, M4R2H6.
